all right this is a bit of an idea cafe
or maybe not i just use that graphic
where there's a continuation from last
week where we were talking about
having a project that actually pays the
bills both for our projects it can fund
new projects and actually gives
us a living wage or whoever's working on
it a living wage um
and i did reach out to raymond and he
didn't really respond so i don't know
whether it's just
stuff going on or or what's up with that
but um
he's not here so we're on our own for
that at the moment
but i'm sure we can figure out maybe we
do it like an idea cafe we can each take
a turn to share and offer
ideas and what we think would be the
most income generating
easiest solution we have yet to fly talk
about or have already talked about
yeah i guess i haven't thought that much
about income
raising i mean i know we talked about it
last time
but it's always for me it's always still
kind of incidental
um for doing
doing what i want to do and then still
how can we
make it sustainable but
you know angels had some ideas on things
that are specifically profitable and
i've gotten a lot of interest on the um
rating system um still i guess i haven't
figured out
who would want to pay for it but uh
so maybe that doesn't apply but every
time i talk to someone
they're like oh yeah i could use that
for x
so i guess i don't have that much except
i would like to
find a sustainable way to work on these
projects full time
like the stepping forward stepping
backwards we all muted and bentley was
off mute so he had to share first
a little bit of chicken um how to make
money
i mean i'm kind of obsessed with not
making money like the anti-money person
i'm like you want to pay me for that
that's gonna make it less fun
but i also really want to be able to
support
ourselves and other people who are
coming into this space and i definitely
want to be able to support the projects
i mean that's where
i'm focused on creating things from the
ground up so everyone can put in a
little bit of money and that's a very
powerful amount
um income generating ones to me are the
ones that
sell on the site right so like the labor
platform
where a tiny percentage is going to the
pool something that does
solve a problem and hopefully in a
cooperative way that is game b
because then even if there's already a
saturated marketplace
there's the incentive
oh i can't think of where it is the like
niche of the market is like we're doing
it better because you can be involved
and you can see it and it's transparent
and i think most people but still game a
right still marketed still beautiful
still functional still working
so that it's still going out to people
right if we created our own taskrabbit
or whatever then
having making sure that people know this
one exists so that they can come to this
one and what makes us different
we're working together to make sure our
workers get paid and
you have you know that we can coordinate
it so you were paying the least amount
as the payer
and you know rating systems and
everything that makes sense um
and then i can't i mean there's a few
ones like that at one point i wanted to
make an
i like global online credit union
because like a financial industry
thing that was that's way too big though
like i mean i can't even figure out to
get 10 000 people including a hundred
thousand dollar project
and a credit you'll be like a million
dollar project but there's a lot
of money in financial endeavors and
doing them in a game
a game b way possibly doing something
like a
micro loan or a loan something that is
a pool of money and we all decide where
it goes to find the next project
but again we need a large number of
people or we all need to already be rich
win the lottery that's my last
contribution
all right uh yeah i kind of waited
because i i mean
i've obviously got opinions on this um
so i think the it sounds like the main
thing that this is about is where do we
start because there's a bunch of options
and i've even got ideas you know that i
think could still be good
but they require kind of a more
significant time and resource
investment um that would be easier if we
already had something making money
um you know so it's the whole like it
takes money to make money thing
um so i mean to me i think the easiest
starting point is still
a salesforce app just because it's not
sort of a
from scratch project and you've got a
built-in
you know possible customer base um
[Music]
open two other ideas as well but to me
that sort of seems like the easiest
next step um i'm not sure how much we
want to talk about just the individual
things that could make money
one of the questions i have is sort of
if you know tomorrow we could snap our
fingers and have a project making some
money
part of the question then becomes how do
we spend it like what part of it goes
towards staff costs
and then you know if let's say okay
we've got two or three people employed
but then we've got some money left over
and you know what does reason score get
what does
election get how do we bring on new
projects and decide what they get
sort of how does that work and i think
that's an important part of
if one of the differentiators of this
platform
is you know if we actually get to
something like a taskrabbit where that's
a part of it is we're offering a service
and we take a small cut um
i think that's a part of how we explain
it is okay here's you know how that
money is being spent
but then when it comes to the projects
here's how those choices are made here's
you know what projects were funding
here's what those
projects have to be like here's what
they can't be like
um that that kind of thing
and then i think one of the other
questions i have is if we're talking
about
i mean this is really starting to
compete in game a with sort of
some game b bits and pieces
part of it is how game a are we how
game b are we how do we move that needle
um and then in the interim how do we
compete with game a companies for
both customers and for talent like if
there's a role that
you know if you could if you were like
the kind of person that we'd want to
fill that role
but you could go work for you know for
google or a big company and be making
well into six figures and
the initial sort of thing that we had
said last time was you know sort of like
paying people a decent wage
but also kind of trying to cap the top
end
what like are we saying everyone makes
the same or are we just saying that
they don't make the same but there's
like a lower multiple where you know
even the ceo shouldn't
be be making 30 times what
uh staff do or you know into the
hundreds of times if we're talking about
what the lowest paid person gets versus
the ceo
those are sort of the things that come
to mind when i think about
how this whole thing works um which i
think might be outside of the
topic of what we said this was which i
think the topic was just sort of how do
we make money
but i think part of that goes into how
do we market
or how do we position this organization
and a lot of it comes to answering those
questions
i think
so yeah i think um i think governance
i like how to how to spend that once you
get it is pretty
big i mean i guess we have some kind of
ideas is that it's not going to be
you know the first couple people that
create it take home all the cash and
stuff um
and then yeah so that i think that as a
whole that will be a whole another topic
that we have to figure out
um also just something else on starting
um a lot of the kind of the
uh in startups for the rest of us they
suggest a stair-step approach so start
with something simple especially if
you've never started a business before
even with like some sort of
um content or educational material you
know where you can just write up a
pdf and sell it so you do some research
and figure out what people want to know
you sell that and then
you know progressively make it bigger
which of course one of those step
bigger things is making a plug-in like
adrian mentioned for
salesforce or something similar
wordpress
and then you can step up to creating you
know actual apps and sas
offerings so that's just an idea i don't
know if there's any i don't know that we
need to start smaller than the
salesforce plugins
and i guess also it might be good to
have some place to like
throw down ideas or even ideas from
other people in game b
just a spreadsheet somewhere might be a
good idea um
yeah and then think through which ones
could we better
serve that that would have an edge being
from game b
either it's cheaper because you're not
being extractive
or it just operates substantially more
efficiently
someone mentioned to me in another
meeting that on that
thing where you can rate companies that
a lot of companies have a vested
interest to make sure that you can't
directly compare their products to
someone else
which also means we have to figure out
lawsuits and stuff like that but
or legal production but i hadn't really
thought about it now that's kind of a
game
a problem right
um so any area where a game a
company couldn't enter
or is a place that's not entered because
their game a principles don't allow them
to
might if if there's if one of those
ideas kind of fits that then that would
be
optimal
because i don't know how how legal it is
i haven't looked into it but one of the
other beautiful things that we have
going for us as we
are a global community and so if
something isn't legal in the states but
it's still ethical because we're game b
people then having that come out of
canada or australia or europe
so that it is legal there right like if
you can compare products in europe
and you're allowed to enter products in
in
the united states because that's what
it's part of right
like you just need to take a picture to
enter a product and that would be
anyway yeah that we can we
a global community can have workarounds
for legality because that's what
the big corporations do right it's just
you can see us doing it we're we're the
people getting together and doing it and
we're doing it ethically right like
there's no ethical reason not to be able
to do that that's all
game a legal but you'll heard our bottom
line
they'll see it causes cancer i worked
really hard on this
i think two panties point one of the
early things will definitely be starting
to get some
sort of legal clout because i fully
expect like if we actually
like for something like a salesforce app
that wouldn't matter but once we
actually start like comparing companies
and even things like having
like you know for wiki election for
example having profiles online
of people can get murky when it comes to
things like gdpr
and that sort of thing where i imagine
that they'll be fighting even harder
against it
because they don't want their profile
online they don't want a permanent sort
of
you know their permanent record online
they want to you know that's fine to
track it for citizens
but for us well wait hold on we don't
want that
um so yeah i do think that
one of the and that's probably a good
example of so if we're talking about
like
maybe something like customer support we
would probably have them like you know
in most companies that's
one of the lower paid roles so we want
to be able to decide
what's the lowest pay that we're we're
willing to go
um you know so sort of how high is that
and then you get into something like
bull
okay if we say let's just say for
example that's 80 000
okay but then what do company lawyers
make because paying a lawyer 80 000 is
almost the same as nothing as far as
they're concerned in most cases because
they
i have an idea and i don't know if it
would be a sales force one though but
you're the sales sports person
so marketing is one of the big game a
things it's one of
um people like the company spends a lot
of marketing to accrue
a customer and it's like salesforce's
whole business is why it might not be a
sales force thing
but to be able to even offer that to
game
a businesses right as gay may as they
are to be like we
you want to find your right customer
right like the person who's going to be
able to find you
how much does it cost right now to get a
customer
we have a we don't yet but we have a uh
a customer base of people who tell us
their values tell us what they're
looking for
and we're telling them the best option
right we're doing it in the game b way
this who
you act this is solves both of your
problem right this is omni win
they're looking for you and you're
looking for them we're working really
for the for the customer the member
but getting paid by connecting them to
the business that is that is best right
so if they pay
five bucks per accrual we're like hey
you're gonna pay us 450
right or like something so there's
having a savings our person's happy and
we're getting paid
is that anything
you have to be careful with that because
that's often where
things tend to go wrong that's because
then you
have an incentive and i want to say
that's a reason not to do it but you
have an incentive to
push people towards the companies that
will pay you if it's an open service not
everyone every company will
um now you know there are like affiliate
programs to where
um like amazon or whatever um
so taking advantage of those that are
already out there would be good
um but
yeah yeah i have to figure out
transparency and how to make sure that
no timer
is anything being which if it's fully
transparent
then it'd be obvious if you mocked with
it
so yeah i'm not sure i could think of a
way outside of just taking advantage of
what already is in game a
that wouldn't cause perverse incentives
yeah and there are a few services like
that already that i think to bentley's
point you can sort of see
they started out well-intentioned and
just you know probably just
somebody's project up the side of their
desk trying to
you know compare companies and then
pretty quickly it got into oh this is
actually a
really lucrative basket of information
that
they can sell and then it you know got
to like allowing companies to pay to
improve their ranking and that sort of
thing i think
if you had almost like embedded in just
how it works that you
that you couldn't do that i'm not sure
what that would look like
there's definitely advantages but it
would be
a there's a lot of people in that space
and b
it would be you know easy to go get
right
might be someone who already does this
but one of so you know my
current rabbit hole is mlms which is of
course the they have people who are like
cult like passionate about the project
selling it to people who are like the
last people you should trust
but anyway then a lot of influencer
marketers right who get paid to try a
product
a lot of times they do really like it
but they're getting paid to do it
to be able to have a third party where
they or the company itself right the
makeup company preview company whatever
it is i don't care how ethical it is i
do
i don't um that they're saying we want a
hundred people to try this
and we're the third party in between to
say okay we're going to give it to these
groups we're going to give an
honest review right these are the makeup
influencers
and they give an honest review and so
their reputation the influencers
reputation is like that they do it
honestly and they're not necessarily
getting paid from the company itself
and then you can actually trust it much
more and so there's there's there's that
built into it
but the the issue would be right you're
giving it to 10 influencers in that case
or 100 random people to try it
to say whether or not they like it and
they're paying for that
right they're paying to say yes this is
third party
these people like it
yeah another option might be just to
allowed to have
paid sponsorship so they just get
displayed as blank is sponsoring this
and of course sponsoring a game b
project
would be pro game b i mean that that
would be something people would like
so they might get that additional
that feature on the system so if you're
searching oh i want to search for
businesses that promote gabby well then
we would be one of the the ways that
they could do that so maybe that's it's
less direct than a pay per
connection but that might be a way
of course one thing i hadn't thought
about too much about all this is how to
keep the system from being gamed
i don't know i talked about that a
little bit but i just got
it's just filling my mind oh and i may
have to leave early so if i disappear
just ignore it
you're a mute dude
i was saying if you had the brick wall
you could disappear back into it but
yeah
oh that's muted and i think that
happened before we went we went live
oh yeah i mean this the point of this
conversation was just to spark ideas to
say what it what it was because it's
more of the idea cafe not the together
tech um board meeting but it i'm okay
with it of course however
it goes
the third party someone's watching this
someone needs to take that on someone
needs to
create a way that we can actually trust
the durability
and comparing them and because even like
the influencers themselves right the
ones that are doing it well
and have the youtube channels you don't
know that
right so you don't know whether they're
being sponsored or not and so
to have that third party in between to
be like okay you're the electronics
people
so you're getting these electronics and
your job is to give them an honest
review
not to do a sponsorship so like
yeah having that that trust built in the
electronics one wants people to
it's basically free advertising that you
pay for once and then people are going
to constantly look up these reviews
but you're going to get honest reviews
so even going through that third party
is going to get you credibility
right that like oh we're willing to do
it this way instead of the other way
it'll be interesting to see how you
could sort of re-envision
the not even sponsorship but like the
review and sort of like what it is using
sponsorships because
they changed the rules on youtube and i
think it might just be like a u.s law
now
where now like if you're sponsored you
have to say it clearly
um and a lot of people have gotten in
trouble for not doing that um
but i wonder if you could sort of say i
think this may have been what you were
getting at jubilee
where like a company contacts this third
party you know or like a proxy like
where it's a company and say hey
you know you make i don't know baby food
so either we just deal
with one or ideally you you may even try
to reach out you know like three or five
companies
and then you know you get their sample
products they the proxy
and then that company arranges with a
bunch of influencers to say
hey here's you know three to five kinds
of baby food
do a review on it you you don't know who
they are or you know or what they're
paid or what they cost or anything just
say like what do you like and then the
proxy knows you know here's product
abcde
in the end you can say hey here's you
know we we send this to 30 different
people
here's you know you can watch the actual
videos of each but then also here's the
summary of
oh if people didn't know what it was
they still picked you know this brand
half the time
i don't think game a companies would pay
for that because there's a difference
between my baby food is okay
and my baby food is the best because
it's like one is just like does the baby
like it
right the other one's like wait is it if
they have these six to choose from do
they choose it well if there's six you
have a one in six chance right like
there's a different
incentive just like pricing would didn't
definitely change
you wouldn't be able to make as much as
because with the sponsorship
it's not a true review like you
probably aren't going to get paid if you
try it you're like oh this sucks like
and if you did get paid no one's ever
going to use you for sponsorship again
but if you had like each of the six
companies
pays one-sixth of what they normally
would it is kind of a gamble
it's saying hey put your money where
your mouth is you're saying that that
your product
is decent if you want to be a part of
this
and i i think to your point yeah it
would be hard to get companies involved
to
at least to start with because it's a
new thing you're saying hey spend money
you might get nothing out of this and i
think like you probably want some sort
of
uh a limit on the bottom part where like
if you've got five companies
maybe you only say like the the top two
or three and you don't say who
the bottom ones are just so that you
aren't like hey we we
we we we paid money for this and we got
ranked as the bottom of six
yeah i'm never doing that again and like
other companies
might be like i don't want part of that
but if you just paid money and you've
got
you know no good out of it but also no
bad
then it might not be as bad and whereas
the company that
paid the same as everyone else and got
ranked top
they might do quite well and so that
might be enough to say okay well it is a
bit of a gamble
but what you get out of it is possibly
good enough
i was thinking it was like the company
itself would let's say give 100 headsets
to to
us the company the third party we would
know which ones to give it to would be
randomized and they would go out to 100
different influencers 100 different
electronics ones
they would just give a review on a
headset right which is normally what
they do they don't necessarily compare
headsets because there's way too many on
the market anyway
they might compare it to the last one
they tried or like this is like
they know headsets because they've tried
out so many of them so they kind of
already know what that
curve is to give their opinion based on
it but they're doing it in a non in
less biased way they they get the
product for free
they get you know and maybe they're not
even paid i don't know maybe that is all
they get
is because they're that is their point
of their channel right is to give
reviews and to give them honestly so
they're
they're audience fully trusts them more
and they get free product but not in a
way that influences their
their right that is and then the the
company itself gave away 100 free
headsets
they don't get to choose who gets it and
who's going to do that and but they get
that stamp of hey
these people reviewed your headset
actually it's not as good of quality as
you think it is
actually or you know like this this or
this and
there could also be because all these
people are doing it we can collect that
data and give that to our customers
right that like hey out of all these
people who
tried this headset they writed it this
way and
whereas this headset is rated
differently and start collecting that
data like it but if you have
single-sided deafness
you actually want this one if you have
if you're listening to music the music
ones wanted this one and the gamers
wanted this one
interesting
so it sounds a bit like maybe it's not
like it's a little bit for marketing
because if you you know if the company
was picked as the top one they're
probably going to include that in in
in advertising but but it sounds like a
lot of it is just sort of like end user
testing
or like hey if you actually want real
feedback
on your products and not like to pay as
you know to pay someone to figure it out
you can already do that now you you know
you you possibly already are
but if you want this kind of feedback
then we can offer that
yeah because i mean we i think the
customer is starting to understand that
five-star reviews aren't five-star
reviews right even on yelp even on
amazon
so sending it out to 100 people who are
both rating it honestly and you can have
a special stamp we don't have control
over yelp and google
but a special stem saying this is a
third-party independent study and yeah
the
people themselves it's really hard just
like you have a better business bureau
stamp or that kind of thing to say
we're really good are you
are you worth that price point are you
durable i mean they're not honestly
gonna know durability
but even that can be reported later on
awesome
and google does actually have a format a
way that you can if you run a rating
site
say what the rating is and then if
someone google searches
and if your page happens to come up in
the ranking
the the rating will display where the
text is
and i think it's often uses stars or
something so it's pretty visible
um yeah i'm just trying to think that
there's an
alternative that doesn't have such a
it's still kind of
we're kind of fitting a round peg and a
square peg and a round hole
kind of the feeling we're trying to
find a place to build sustainability
um and i think further to that point
a lot of the stuff that we've talked
about so far requires an audience
and part of it is we kind of need money
to get an audience
or at least to help like grow it and to
get and to possibly hire somebody
that together tech and the projects can
use to sort of figure out hey what could
help us build audiences for together
tech four reason score four-week
election
for solution raising for all of them um
and so i think that's where there are a
bunch of different
avenues that we could use to start
making money but i think part of it is
which of them
already require us to either have an
audience or money and then which of them
are like oh we could do this now
and i guess some of the unspoken options
is you know having a tour people can
optionally pay
for access to the service um
maybe you can get deeper i still like
that i don't like putting part of the
feature set behind the wall
but deeper analytics when you're
searching for
things um
yeah i don't know maybe the individual
people could hire people to go and do
research for them
where they can describe what they want
and then you know then we need to hire
someone to
to go out look at all the products put
them in the system
that might be something so it'd be more
like they're sponsoring it to be put in
the system because that data wouldn't
just go to that person although
a lot of times it may be very personal
if someone is looking for a nanny that
can do
sign language right you know there's not
enough
people that would value that in the main
system you'd still kind of put it there
but
and then also that would kind of
bootstrap the system as well
to get data in it but
yeah and then just have a you know a
badge on the site that's
you know we say you know we expect
x percent of your income or something
you know we suggest
a donation of x percent of your income
and if you're if you're paying some
money
then uh there'd be some sort of
indicator so as you're
interacting with community or other
people are seeing your reviews
your information you're putting in there
might be an indicator there
i don't really know if that would
actually go anywhere though
i wonder if one of the things we kind of
um alluded to it earlier on
is to like just brainstorm everything
that could make money
whatever sell our children you know like
like every
things that were and then how on how
game a how game b
they are how complicated they are and
how much they require us to have more of
an audience than we do now
right how long are they take to make is
there that beta version
and there might be one that pops out as
oh this is an obvious winner or
there might be an obvious no there's a
reason we haven't made this yet
there's r and uh like figure out what
those categories are that we'd want to
score and then
also put it out to the game b community
of hey
we have the same problem again and again
that we can't finance projects that
people need to be able to be paid
in order to be able to fund game b
projects we're looking to start one
to make living wages and fund future
projects
it needs to be profitable like that is
the reason of this right the reason of
this isn't necessarily to create game b
that's why we're doing it that's the why
later um and including right how could
this be gamified how could this
how game a is it and how could it be
even more gameplay that we maybe can't
see
right yeah so i'd almost rather say
i mean we so we could pursue adriel's
ideas but also maybe putting out to the
game b communities let's brainstorm
products and services that we personally
would
pay for and then we take a look at those
and see which of those have an advantage
in the game a market
because it's game b and maybe see if we
can
brainstorm with the larger group that's
a good
a good idea one of the so one of the
things with the essential oil thing that
i'm also obsessed with
is um i'm working on like the idea of a
video between like what an mlm essential
oil company does a for-profit one and a
cooperative one and like what
what what does the customer get what
does the business owner get what does
the planet get from those three
doing something similar to that where
we're all living in game a anyway
like you said what would you use as a
service but also like
how do we make it cooperative right how
do we take well we're all using toilet
paper
how do we make a hemp toilet paper that
like would go to everyone in north
america that's in game b
how much would it need to be parole how
much would there need to be are we
willing to put it out to our family and
friends right like it might even be
something that is an act not a tech
project right that is um it's one of the
things that came up during our climate
change solution raising
that that daniel had mentioned is that
like picking one product to make super
carbon neutral whatever whatever right
so toilet paper seems temp toilet paper
seems like an obvious to me like
but something like that right that is
what do you use
that you want to be made better and then
which one has the highest rating right
like if i'm not willing to change my
toilet paper there's no point
but if hey game b is going to have a
toilet paper brand would you be willing
to switch over
yes if it was the same or less money or
to
get it delivered right like whatever
those those metrics are but starting
with something that is
game a slash game b right like a toilet
paper company that
i think fights and wipes away the shit
of game a
at the same time
your marketing slogan there yeah i think
one of the
things that would i think would need to
be a part of this
is sort of the like hey what ideas do
you have that might be able to be used
you know to make money to be able to pay
for game b projects
but then also what would it need to look
like in order for you to be willing you
know to share
ideas that you think are because i think
a lot of people they're kind of both
gaming and game b at the same time like
game b sounds good
but also right now existing in game a
and also
some people are liars and some people
might be you know pretending to be game
b and then they get a game
idea and say actually never mind game a
is great and then they just switch to
making money
um so i think part of it is both the
question of
what you know ideas could we move
forward with that would be
you know sort of our next steps that we
could feasibly do
right now or soon um but then also if
you have ideas like that
what would you need to see from that
organization like what would it need to
be structured like
in order for you to participate
um and that might end up i think there's
sort of at least two different sides
there's like
just the idea and there's also the like
actually participate and you know keep
like sort of
actively work on it um
and then you know i guess there's sort
of two different
versions of that there's like what would
it take for you to work on a project now
and participate
and you wouldn't really get anything out
of it unless it was successful and
you're
like you're still sort of taking all the
same risk that you would in game a
but then possibly not getting as much of
a payout versus
what could you do you know what would
the organization have to to look like
for you to participate but also keep in
mind that organization is helping to
alleviate some of that risk like if it's
able to
you know have staff help or if it's
actually able to
contribute some money towards it then
that is an obvious thing we're like oh
so that's how it's different from game a
it's kind of like an investor but it's a
new kind of
investing sort of both of those steps
if that makes sense i think that is
important one of the things
like when you start have a startup
especially a tech startup it's very
common that you you
um don't get paid because the idea you
get that big payoff in the end right so
with the mlms all of it it's like oh i'm
taking on all this time and risk
even though i don't think it's time to
rise to become rich one day
that there's like a collective vision
which is what game b is
right that is like this is humanity's
richness right like this humanity
getting to be on a yacht and a mansion
it's our equivalent we're not getting
all its mansions right like what
what does that future need to look like
for you that it's it's
enough of an incentive that you put time
in right and how little or much time is
that right like for solution raisings
i'm like you get envisioned a better
world it's literally an hour a week i
don't understand
i don't understand it's not money it's
not it but
like they don't even know it's a
possibility they don't
know what those things are
hello hello hello sorry for me it is
part of the very interesting
conversation from the subject
suggests money money money
we're getting very game a up in here
figuring out how to make money
not really we're still game b people so
what's the idea
it's still generally oh yeah i think
we talked through a few ideas but we
thought maybe best to do a
survey of game b people
ask him what products would they be
willing
i'd almost phrased it as
what products would you be willing to
pay a little more for
if it was a game b company that was
non-extractive
because i think we know if we can do for
less of a price
then everyone would in game be they'd be
more likely to do it
and then or but also maybe ask them the
question what are some products that you
think
products or services that you think that
if it was done by a game b
company it would have an edge
in the game a marketplace that because
we're not being extractive
or because other than the fact that
people in game b
would use it like we might get some sort
of
edge like there i think there's some
businesses that
just don't work because people want to
protect their
intellectual property right but since
we wouldn't care so much about the
intellectual property i mean someone
could steal the idea and redo it
um that maybe we can do stuff like that
so just
i guess kind of just think through what
are some
what are some market advantages that the
gamebee philosophy
naturally has
i think that's a good more focused like
asking gamebee what products they'd be
willing to pay a little bit more for for
and more omni win solution
and instead of and then if you because
because i don't think anyone needs an
incentive to give that idea i'm not
telling you i want toilet paper you
might steal it right like there's
it's more and then that other part is an
important part for later for together
attack right like if you have an amazing
idea what would get you to bring it here
it's like two different
i guess also there might be some
business areas where people would be
also be willing to pay more
but because it's a game b company you
know
maybe like if there's an industry where
it's traditionally done
through slave labor or oppressive labor
in other countries right
then that would be something that i mean
already some companies are using that
but it'd be like a tom shoes or
something like that
where yeah
so so far the sort of different aspects
that i'm seeing to this conversation
is what are the projects that we could
do now versus later so what's sort of
like a next step that we could do
without needing money and resources and
an audience
versus like obviously if we have time
and money and audience people
working on a project there's different
things that we could do
there's the question of what like actual
idea do you have for you know
a company product service or whatever
versus just
what products would you buy if they were
better in certain of the
these aspects um and then
from that question is what would the
organization or products need to
to look like what would be the unique
aspects either for you to feel safe
contributing your idea
or that you would be more willing to
spend your money as a consumer with that
organization
um and then the part of like
which product or service or company
would get an advantage because of its
game b
attributes like being omni winner being
anti-rival risks that sort of thing
versus just which do we think would do
better because the company is sort of
that game b
feel good market positioning like the
the tom shoes
as far as i know that's purely sort of
uh people want to contribute in that way
not so much because of the way it's made
it has some innate
advantage that's sort of the four
different parts to this
question that i can see right now
what product would you buy or what
service would you like to subscribe to
right i'm just thinking what services
would be the most beneficial tool uh
game b type people new facebook
obviously
but um
yeah and i think one of the traps that
we could really easily fall into here
is the example that jubilee gave with
mounting with mountain equipment co-op
where they asked their members hey what
do you want and the members told them
and then they went and built this new
fancy thing you know with less
slave labor and less environmental
impact the people said great that's too
expensive i'm gonna go buy it from
walmart
okay and so i think part of it is how do
we avoid that
how do we actually you know if we're
going to go through the effort of doing
the research and making
the the thing which i think no matter
what any time that that we're making a
product
that's going to be later because we have
to go through like the
investment of you know the procurement
and the creation and the marketing and
the actual
shipping of things um if you do well
enough you
can get people to pre-order so
true and that is like i i matush
actually use the word subscription and i
think that
is a good that's a good system right
that there's like the dollar shave club
and stuff to do
what kind of things in your life would
you put in a subscription for that
you're
we know what the you know what i mean
you're gonna order detergent every month
it doesn't mean you're committing to
that for the rest of your life
but like yes i want laundry detergent i
want toothpaste
i want this thing and even going out and
doing more of a buyer's club
where we're actually looking for what's
already on the market
and offering like like bulk buying it
and then putting it out into
into like here's the top 10 right
toothpaste deodorant whatever whatever
um and getting them subscription where
it's like
i'm maybe going down rabbit holes but
subscription is what's that
well that's interesting doing a group
buyers
we may be too spread out for the real
benefits of that to be but maybe
maybe not um but that's interesting
because we'd have a similar kind of
rubric or decision making for what
products to buy not exactly
because people are different needs but
but yeah maybe if we know that
you know they're this this of all the
companies this is the least extractive
and maybe using the tool we were talking
about where people give feedback
so the group would come together i
really think also using reason score to
make that decision
would be helpful because people put in
all the evidence they know about the
company and then
based on that i would come to a group
decision on which
company to buy the products is the
expense is the delivery
right it's like collecting the stuff
both buying it and delivery
and in that it's like right you get it
once per month right everyone gets it
like maybe you actually go pick it up
from a warehouse in vancouver right
maybe that is part of what makes
it cheap or you're paying extra to get
it delivered directly to your house
but like it's that it goes to vancouver
right so i get my toothpaste my
deodorant my whatever whatever
i can pick it up for my neighborhood
that there's
ways that we can do this together that
don't necessarily have to look like
amazon or
you know and nick
had some similar things uh
where he was figuring out areas for
people to work together in
i don't know if that could be leveraged
as well
i'll say one of the things i like about
the buyers club is
that if we're pooling money together to
say like hey let's you know go buy shoes
or toothpaste or well
whatever there's a i think you have the
vacuum or something happening in the
background
so you're not talking
there we go
one of the interesting things about a
buyer's club is that if let's say
you know we say okay let's go out and do
a toothpaste
subscription that i think is an easier
way to have the conversation around
what would the organization or the
product need to look like what are the
unique aspects
because you aren't talking theoretical
then you're saying like no no we have 10
options
what questions do we need to ask to be
able to pick one
um and then you know you might end up
with something like reason score where
you say
okay we identified these five you know
attributes that we want to be able to
score on and then there's
there's both the here's how those are
scored and then here's how the group has
weighted things based on our
understanding of what the group wants
we're gonna pick this one who's still in
because you might say like oh i'm
interested in the idea of a buyer's club
but i just you know really don't agree
with the attributes that we picked for
for toothpaste so i'm gonna skip out
on this one but at the very least you've
got those attributes and you've got some
of the the scoring happening
and that i think is a way better way to
have that conversation than just a
theoretical hey what would a company
look like for you to want to be able to
buy things from them
which is way too nebulous for i think
people to really
resonate with and you know pay attention
to an answer
i like the idea that was coming up
because of my mlm obsession right now is
like having a city sign up for
like once you have 100 people in a city
that's when it starts right like that's
when you can get it
delivered to that city and then you know
there's five or six products that you
get and you can buy like
it's based on the volunteer hours of the
people going and sorting those boxes
from
from that space or we sort it into
central location and send it out in
boxes
but that there is we're working to bring
together like what toothpaste is out
there that isn't crest and colgate
what detergent is out there and working
with the companies to be like what we
want is less packaging what we want is
like
you know not to to have sulfites and and
all these things in it
um yeah working with i think it's
omni-win like i think that it's actually
and it's also something that like with
what happens here with the um container
stores and stuff
if you can get stuff that doesn't that
comes in mason jars that you're
you're returning it comes in less
plastic
that is bulk bought because there's
always so expensive it's like yeah i
want a bamboo toothpick like that's
like that is a dollar per toothpick like
they're so expensive and they have to be
like hemp toilet paper
should be what we're all using i don't
understand how it's not but it's because
any company that starts
has to you know go through everything
we're going through and so there's not
the choice on the market whereas if we
can find a hemp
toilet paper company be like hey if we
have 10 000 customers
what's the price that we can offer not
to you know lowball them but to be like
we want people using your product it's a
better product
how do we bring down this cost how do we
can you do it how much
yeah yeah not not have them artificially
bring down the cost but how can we
buy buying in bulk reduce your cost of
production
and pass some of those savings back to
us so they make a slightly more profit
and and and
we're able to make a little profit and
the customers get what
we get what we want there's a company in
the states and i always want to call it
the honest company but it's not the
honest company
um and you pay a subscription fee like
with costco
per year and they're they're creating
food
cosmet like all the stuff that you need
in a household that is environmentally
friendly
like they have their own brand and
they're actually creating it and then
you're getting that stuff at cost
because you're paying a subscription fee
there's something there
but we don't want to make our own
products necessarily that's a lot but
like
that we're doing that same thing where
you're paying a subscription fee to get
this
and we're sourcing it with you and for
you
and then there's that little tiny bit of
a fee on top because this is you know
or or if there isn't because you were
paying the subscription 50 bucks you
might be thinking of brandless
maybe yeah better stuff fewer dollars
sounds right i heard something about
them i thought they were having some
trouble but i don't
um yeah i saw another company that was
showing me ads on facebook a while ago i
don't think it was brand
that that doesn't sound familiar but i
think it was the same basic idea
where it was yeah you pay us monthly we
you know are making stuff at cost and
blah blah blah
the issue is so how do i trust you right
like you're still
how do i know what's in that product how
do i know what where is
we we can't necessarily say that but we
have the ingredients list
we're not the middle man we're not the
people making the toothpaste and
therefore trying to save money on it
like and i they might be too because
it's about getting giving it a cost so
like being transparent with that cost
we're like look the company told us it's
two bucks yours is 220.
okay like it's it's uh we made it it's
whatever it's the same price is what you
would buy off the website you're getting
it all shipped to us you're not paying
for shipping you're getting it all
at this price and the company gets to
stay in business
yeah so brandless did shut down they had
a funding issue but they're back
open and they're focusing on staying
profitable i think they took
on too much um uh
too much funding and then couldn't
maintain the evaluation and
everything but
also like if you need to have an entire
catalog of goods that you're making
yourself
that is huge especially during this time
whereas finding people that already
doing that and bringing them customers
is a different
and i think colleen and harris might be
the people because they have their
online farmers market there's something
about that that's like hey
what can how does this this go together
in a product
an interesting thing is that part of one
of the things that people like
in this community is um local
and you lose kind of some of these
centralized deficiencies when you go
local so
i don't know if we could think of it'd
be interesting to work with them to see
if there's anything we can think of
to do for the local although if you're
doing it on a city basis like
jubilee suggested then then definitely
local would work
what i was thinking was like you have
the local farmers market right with the
food that's created and you're you're
still delivering to those
to people and so you have what what
they're doing in
a you know beautiful efficient way
creating a website people want to use
you can use between cities as a customer
but the local and then that
same organization is also getting the
the shipment from like i don't know if i
need my toothpaste made locally i might
but you know
like getting those things shipped and
putting your box as well so you're
adding these subscription things onto it
and it's not because it's open and
transparent it's not as high as the cost
as going to whole foods and buying it
and you're not having having to support
bezos right like there's
yeah and we if we have a customer base
of people who care about this this isn't
necessarily even spuds in vancouver
who's still an awesome company but like
i don't really care if they succeed
whereas if it's ours that we own
together that is something that is like
i do care if it succeeds i want to be
able to continue buying this toothpaste
we're helping the little the little
companies the local farmers
and who's not going to sign up for it
right like if it's actually a good
if it's not as expensive as going to the
farmers market and it's
open it gets delivered to you
i was thinking if possible with the like
trying to find people in the same city
what what might be like along that same
route and possibly even more
i guess efficient both with the finding
groups of people and uh
making more efficient within the same
city is finding people like
starting off by targeting people in the
same apartment buildings
so you can say like hey if we can find
five apartment buildings in the same
city you know with at least 20 people
per
per building then things like delivery
become easier we're like oh yeah we can
deliver to you
4x costs where you're now sharing that
delivery with everyone else
in the building and then you just have
to go down to the lobby and pick it up
or you know the delivery could actually
go door-to-door and that that that could
be
built into it and one of the things
would actually be working like
i'm thinking it's harder to find a
building that happens to have a lot of
people who have the same ethics in it
right that are in but you know what
isn't is the people who work for a
specific company so like in vancouver
van city
right like the van city headquarters be
like hey do you want your food delivered
here
and then you i don't know how you do it
as far as keeping it cold throughout the
day so it gets to them but
whatever that it gets like they get it
delivered to their work
they're there during the day and
it's a lot easier to find 20 people
working at vancity who have these values
then 20 people at a random apartment
building has its values right
right that seems like a pretty good
starting point like if it because
i i mean i'm not sure how how many of us
have worked in offices
at least recently but like it was a
fairly common thing to you know
buy lunch together well if you had a
service where the whole purpose was kind
of like a combination of groupon
and ubereats where it was like hey we'll
deliver it to your building and again if
you can schedule it it may be even
better
we can say hey you know we we've
contacted five or ten restaurants
in this area on tuesdays you know you
can get
four tacos for four dollars or whatever
the price ends up being
and so it sort of ends up being that
like there is that innate we're not
actually building anything we're just
looking to get the buyers and sellers
taking a small cut
but like they're like i i would have
loved that when i worked in an office
i also just remembered we're independent
people working
but you know true true different time
maybe we might go back to that yeah so
that might be another point for the
apartment buildings but yeah when we go
back to offices i think that
that that would be because i would have
totally done that if
i if there was some sort of like a
schedule to make it easier on the
restaurants to say hey
we have you know a different restaurant
every day of the week go take a look and
if at least five of you
buy in it's this price and then you can
even have you know if if there's 10 it's
lower if there's 20 inch lower
this is the product right here i mean
finding solutions brainstorming
possibilities i don't know
i don't want to pay for this hard to
monetize
someone yeah but still there are people
who
need solutions for anything crazy yeah
yeah
yeah i wonder about a game
yeah game b thank you management
consulting
game i don't know that we have a lot of
experience yet
um i think that's an option once we have
a couple of like
successful profitable projects under our
belts then we can start to go to
companies or they might actually reach
out to us
i mean we've done project raisings in
the past having people who are a little
more on and being like right for an hour
of our focus time it's 100 bucks right
now that's are we getting paid for our
time are we gonna get 25 bucks an hour
just together in tech to get 100 bucks
right like what is the actual
metrics but hey if you're just starting
out you know 100 bucks because you have
to be serious enough that you're
willing to pay that whereas you know the
bigger ones but i don't know anymore but
yeah and also if it's a if it's a
company wanting to be game b
wouldn't we provide them that advice for
free i mean i guess if it's
though if it's a nominal amount of
money um then it could be kind of like
hey we want to do this for you we're
just asking for a donation
from your company yeah and it might be
like sort of tears on like if you're
actually going full game b yeah we'll
help you for free because then
theoretically we're owners too but if
you're like just trying to say how can i
capitalize on this game b
sentiment while still being a game a
company okay depending how much you're
staying game a
depends how much you would get charged
yeah we're just brain i don't know if
they're here with us but like we're just
brainstorming for them right hey we just
like we just came beat restaurants
several times right so i'm like are we
going to charge every restaurant it's
like you know
like there's you really game be an
entire industry but if
one company in that industry is like no
i want to know how we can have that edge
um well you can because the whole point
is that if you're in competition and
you're gonna keep the other ones out you
don't get it like it's like
but but you're willing to pay then you
get the benefit of what comes out of it
right if you're a restaurant and we're
starting to deliver to
office buildings you get that but so do
other people so do the other restaurants
so we're helping all restaurants i do
think that almost
no matter what the first few solutions
are going to be something tech based
so that it's just innately scalable and
whether that's like an online
solution that that we consulted to the
world or some sort of a tech platform
that helps you know some sort of a local
emphasis
for it to be like truly scalable and i
think that's kind of what the first few
things have to be
that's the vibe i i get is that the
first few should be
so that we can have some funds to to a
you know pay people and to pay for our
projects
but then also to pay for the other
projects to make more money
because once you have money it's easier
to make money
thanks gaming
oh we're almost at the hour
five more minutes let's done three more
minutes
although i think winning the lottery is
still let's just keep buying lottery
tickets what do we think
that's that's viable right go to the
casino
just assume people win
and i see always like
i'm gonna stop thinking about it
as something fitting in this particular
context
but maybe not and also um
there was something in one podcast uh
about gaming and enterprises
uh doing the new style the nv style
um about uh
name eight companies not being able i
mean being
seriously disadvantaged comparing to uh
game b because having shareholders
and uh
the there were reasons why uh a proper
game b
um company should be
much better and more efficient and uh
generally be better than its
game a counterpart
that's on one hand and on the other hand
um
they may has a very serious advantage in
a
form of not having to care about
environment for example
or using slave labor
as
as they see fit for the
making their product so i don't know is
it
that by default the game will be
uh to win the competition is
going to be disadvantaged right from the
start
and it's interesting because that is
some sort of delight the the
pros and cons of each but i think also
that gay may advantage
if we add a layer of visibility through
things like reason score and converati
that starts to dissolve because that is
one of the the things that i'm saying is
people do care it's just not
easy to tell like if a company has a
really bad environmental impact
they don't you know they don't broadcast
that and when it comes out they usually
either have to change it or they get
trounced like they get crushed in the
news and people stop buying from them
and then they have to make a big
spectacle of oh we changed and we
improved this
or they sink well concealing the scenes
is a
very big part of uh of the market
right yeah which i think the touch what
you touched on is the
is that like game a companies have
shareholders that they have to be
profitable for
yes and good and bad that comes with
that we have stakeholders that the more
they're aware they're a stakeholder the
more they're actually inves involved and
aware of it
they trust us more they
care about us succeeding because they
want to be able to create
keep using the product or service
whatever it is we're using
and every kind of innovation goes to
everyone
and so like game b has a big advantage
even in game a but people have to kind
of become aware so what are
like as these other things become more
transparent as we start to that one
starts to diminish
and game b starts to to take off i mean
this is exactly when i when
a year ago before i found game b when i
was talking about dismantling capitalism
like this was
like we could do this from the inside
this is actually like these omni-win
solutions
in and of themselves having stakeholders
with a stake in it versus shareholders
who only care about profit
which one is the customer going to pick
which one is like
the only ones who profit in game are the
shareholders and
the owners and even then you don't
because you're still a stakeholder in
everything else and so yeah that there's
an
advantage anyone else closing thoughts
right all right we're back tomorrow
morning at 9 a.m pacific standard time
for our round table we share what our
projects are and what we've done with
them and what we're going to do in the
next week
all right thank you everybody